So, let's work on the Cart and therefore,
of course, we can go to the Cart folder
and add a Cart.js file for the Cart component.
Now the Cart components should render all the Cart items
and, of course, display the total amount.
And then, also, give us buttons
for leaving the Cart and for ordering,
though for this application, as shown in the preview,
ordering won't really be a thing.
Therefore, here we can add our Cart component function,
expect props and export it, like this.
And attached, you find a Cart.module.css file
with some styling for this Cart.
Hence, we can already import
classes from './Cart.module.css';
and then return the mark-up for the Cart.
Now, here, as I said, in this application
I wanna render this Cart in a modal.
Now, we're going to build this modal in a second though.
You can also try this on your own
also by using React Portals
which is a feature we learned about,
but before we are going to do it together
I wanna finish the general Cart mark-up.
So have a div here, which will later be the modal component,
and inside of that div, or inside of that modal then,
I wanna render my cartitems, here,
and then below that a div with the total amount,
and below that a div with the actions for the Cart,
so the Close and the Order button.
Now, for the cartitems I, again,
will add a little helper constant, here,
cartItems, where I wanna map all cartItems
to cartItem JSX elements.
Now at the moment, we, of course, have no cartItems here.
So, we'll start with a dummy array
which I create inline here,
which will hold a cartItem, let's say with an idea of c1,
with a name of Sushi,
with an amount of two, maybe, and the price of 12.99
and for the moment that's it.
And we then map this array of objects,
which here is just an example.
Later, we will get a real object
managed through React context.
But we will map that item here to a cartItem component
which we also don't have yet.
So, for the moment I'll just output a list item
where I output item.name
and then it's these cartItems which are rendered, here,
cartItems, like this.
And actually, I wanna wrap this in an unordered list
so I will, overall,
set cartItems = to an unordered list
then a opening curly brace
around this JavaScript expression, closing curly brace
and then closing unordered list item.
And I can also already add a class name
on that unordered list and set this to
>{[
written like this because of the dash.
And that's the cartItems which are being output down there.
Now speaking of down there, in that first div, here then,
I wanna have a span where I say Total Amount
and then below that another span
where the actual amount is being output.
And for the moment, I'll just hard code 35.62, here,
but this is something which will, of course,
be derived dynamically later.
On that div I will add a class name of classes.total.
And then we got that other div with the buttons.
This will receive a className of classes.actions
and then in there I wanna have two buttons.
The first button says Close
and I will add a className, here, of classes
and then it's button--alt and because of the dashes,
again, I'm using this syntax of accessing that property.
And then below that I have another button where I say Order
and this will receive a className of classes.button.
Now later, we will only render the Order button
when we have items in the Cart
but since we're working with dummy data, only at the moment,
we don't need to worry about this right now.
Okay, so that's the Cart.
Now, as I said, the Cart should not be inside
of that div though, but inside of a modal.
So, therefore, let's add such a modal wrapper
which renders this Cart as an overlay.
Next, of course, try it on your own first if you want to
and thereafter we're going to do that together.